fromachefskitchen.com 2019-07-17

# Privacy Policy - From A Chef's Kitchen

This Privacy Policy outlines the type of personal information that is received, collected and used by [From A Chef’s Kitchen](https://www.fromachefskitchen.com/).  If you are a resident of the European Union, please note that as we are located in the United States.  Your information is processed outside the European Economic Area (“EEA”).  Regardless of where your personal information is located, the measures we use to protect your personal information is stated below.

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, contact Carol Borchardt at **carol@fromachefskitchen.com  **or at the mailing address under “Who We Are.”

Users can link to this Privacy Policy on our home page, or at a minimum on the first significant page after entering our website.  Our Privacy Policy link includes the word ‘Privacy’ and can be easily found on the page specified above.  Users will be notified of updates to our Privacy Policy on our Privacy Policy page.

Your privacy is of the utmost importance and we are guided by these fundamental principles:

  * We are considerate of the personal information we ask you to provide and the information we collect.  We collect only what is absolutely necessary.
  * Your personal information is stored for only as long as we have reason to keep it.
  * We aim for full transparency on how your information is gathered and used.
  * We do not sell, trade, or otherwise transfer to outside parties your personally identifiable information.
  * Our website is scanned on a regular basis for security holes and known vulnerabilities in order to make your visit to our site as safe as possible.
  * We regularly scan for malware and have an SSL certificate (https).

### WHO WE ARE

[From A Chef’s Kitchen](https://www.fromachefskitchen.com/) is a for-profit food and cooking-related website located in the United States and operated by Carol Borchardt.  Our physical address is:

From A Chef’s Kitchen

P. O. Box 3083

Collierville, TN  38027

  * #### VOLUNTARY USER-PROVIDED INFORMATION

    * BY SUBSCRIBING:  We collect information from you when you subscribe to receive post updates.  The information you will be asked to enter is your e-mail address and only what is necessary to provide you with the requested service.  This information is stored in our e-mail manager, [MailChimp](https://mailchimp.com/legal/privacy/), where it is password protected and only accessible by us.  You may unsubscribe or update your e-mail preferences at any time.
    * BY COMMENTING:  We collect information when you leave a comment on a post.  Your information is stored in our password-protected [WordPress](https://wordpress.org/about/privacy/) database. 
      * You will be asked for your name, e-mail address and website (if any) when leaving a comment.  Your e-mail address is not published nor can it be viewed publicly.
      * Your IP address and browser user agent string are recorded and stored in our password-protected database.  This aids in SPAM detection.  An anonymized string created from your email address (also called a hash) may be provided to the Gravatar service if you are using it.  The Gravatar service privacy policy is available here:  [Gravatar Privacy Policy](https://automattic.com/privacy/).  If you use the Gravatar service, upon approval of your comment, your profile picture is visible to the public in the context of your comment.
      * We use [Askimet](https://automattic.com/privacy/), an automated WordPress plugin to scan comments for SPAM.
      * If you leave a comment, the comment is viewable and its metadata are retained indefinitely.
      * If you correspond with us by e-mail, we may retain the content of your e-mail message, your e-mail address and our response.

  * #### INFORMATION COLLECTED THROUGH COOKIES AND OTHER TECHNOLOGY

    * From A Chef’s Kitchen does not use cookies to monitor or track your behavior while using this website.  (We rely on Google Analytics which is anonymous.  Please see Third Party Analytics Services below.)
    * If you leave a comment on our site you may opt-in to save your name, email address and website in cookies.  These are for your convenience so that you do not have to fill in your details again when you leave another comment.  These cookies will last for one year.
    * Articles on this site may include embedded content (e.g. videos, images, articles, etc.).  Embedded content from other websites behaves in the exact same way as if the visitor has visited the other website.  These websites may collect data about you, use cookies, embed additional third-party tracking and monitor your interaction with that embedded content, including tracing your interaction with the embedded content if you have an account and are logged in to that website.
    * **COOKIE OPT OUT:   **You may opt out of all cookies using the Network Advertising Initiative opt-out page at this page:  <http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/>
  * #### **LOG FILE INFORMATION**

    * Log file information is automatically reported by your browser each time you access a web page.  The information inside the log files includes internet protocol (IP) addresses, type of browser, Internet Service Provider (ISP), date/time stamp, referring/exit pages, and the number of clicks to analyze trends, administer the site, track user’s movement around the site and gather demographic information.  IP addresses and other such information are not linked to any information that is personally identifiable.

  * #### THIRD PARTY ANALYTICS SERVICES

    * From A Chef’s Kitchen uses the third-party analytics services of [Google Analytics](https://policies.google.com/privacy).   **The settings for From A Chef’s Kitchen analyze data anonymously.   **User and event data is retained for a period of 26 months.  For more information about how Google handles the data and how you may opt out, see [How Google Uses Information From Sites or Apps That Use Our Service](https://policies.google.com/technologies/partner-sites).

  * #### SOCIAL MEDIA PLATFORMS

    * From A Chef’s Kitchen is integrated with the following third-party social media networks where we may receive information about you if you “like,” follow or comment: 
      * Facebook
      * Twitter
      * Pinterest
      * Bloglovin
      * Google Plus
      * Instagram
      * Linked In
      * StumbleUpon
      * Tumblr
    * If you interact with us through a social media platform, you may be granting us on-going access to certain information.  If you do not want a social media platform to collect or share information about you, please refer to the privacy policy and settings of the applicable social media property before using such features on our website.

### HOW WE USE YOUR INFORMATION

We use the personal information you submit or that we collect to operate, maintain and provide you with our subscription features and commenting functionality.

By providing us with your email address, you acknowledge we may use the e-mail address to send you our subscription-related service or other service-related notices including any notices required by law.  The e-mail is in lieu of communication by postal mail.

If you wish to discontinue receiving such email messages, you may opt-out or change your preferences on the e-mail message at any time.  Your e-mail address will be retained in our password-protected e-mail database for analytics purposes only and you will never receive another e-mail from us.  Please contact Carol Borchardt at  **carol@fromachefskitchen.com** to have your information permanently deleted.

### HOW YOUR INFORMATION IS POTENTIALLY SHARED

  * We will not rent or sell your personal information to others.  Ever.
  * Any personal information you voluntarily disclose when commenting on a post becomes available to the public.
  * Except as otherwise described in this Privacy Policy, we will not disclose your personal information to any third party unless required to do so by law or subpoena.
  * **THROUGH ADVERTISING**
    * **TARGETING AND USE OF THIRD-PARTY ADVERTISING COMPANIES:   **We use [Mediavine](https://www.mediavine.com/), a third-party advertising network to serve ads when you visit our website.  These ad networks may use aggregated information about your visit such as pages you have visited, links you followed and other websites you’ve visited in order to provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to you.  You can review Mediavine’s Privacy Policy [HERE](https://www.mediavine.com/privacy-policy/).  You may view a list of Mediavine’s ad partners and their privacy policies [HERE](https://www.mediavine.com/gdpr/).  If you would like more information about this practice and to know your choices about not having this information used by these companies, please see: [http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp](http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp)
    * **AMAZON ASSOCIATE DISCLOSURE:   **The owner of this website, Carol Borchardt, is a participant in the Amazon Services, LLC Associates Program, an affiliate advertising program designed to provide a means for sites to earn advertising fees by advertising and linking fromachefskitchen.com to Amazon properties.  All affiliate links will be clearly disclosed.  Clicking on and purchasing a product from one of these links does not result in any additional cost to you.  You may review Amazon’s privacy policy [HERE](https://www.amazon.com/gp/help/customer/display.html/ref=footer_privacy?ie=UTF8&nodeId=468496).
    * **SPONSORED CONTENT TRACKING PIXELS:   **From A Chef’s Kitchen may engage in sponsored campaigns with various influencer networks, brands, and agencies.  All sponsored content is duly disclosed in accordance with the FTC’s requirements.  From time to time, these sponsored campaigns utilize tracking pixels (aka web beacons), which may contain cookies to collect data regarding usage and audience.  This information is collected by the sponsoring company to track the results of the campaign.  No personally identifiable information collected by these pixels is used in conjunction with these tracking pixels.

### HOW WE PROTECT YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION

We care about the integrity and security of your personal information and have implemented appropriate technical security measures to safeguard your personal information such as access to our e-mail manager is password-protected.  You are responsible for maintaining the secrecy of your e-mail account information and for controlling access to your email communications from From A Chef’s Kitchen.

Our website is scanned on a regular basis for security holes and known vulnerabilities in order to make your visit to our site as safe as possible.  We regularly scan for malware and have an SSL certificate (https).

### IF YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION IS COMPROMISED

In the event that your personal information is compromised as a result of a breach of security, we will promptly notify those persons whose personal information has been compromised, in accordance with the notification procedures set forth in this Privacy Policy or as otherwise required by applicable law.

The Fair Information Practices Principles form the backbone of privacy law in the United States and the concepts they include have played a significant role in the development of data protection laws around the globe.  Understanding the Fair Information Practice Principles and how they should be implemented is critical to comply with the various privacy laws that protect personal information.  In order to be in line with Fair Information Practices should a data breach occur, we will notify the users via email within 72 hours.

We also agree to the individual redress principle, which requires that individuals have a right to pursue legally enforceable rights against data collectors and processors who fail to adhere to the law.  This principle requires not only that individuals have enforceable rights against data users, but also that individuals have recourse to courts or a government agency to investigate and/or prosecute non-compliance by data processors.

### YOUR RIGHTS AND CHOICES ABOUT YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION

YOU MAY AT ANY TIME:

  * Decline to submit personal information and use our website anonymously.
  * Update or correct your email preferences at any time.  You may also e-mail  **carol@fromachefskitchen.com** to have this done.  Your request will be handled promptly.
  * Unsubscribe from emails at any time.  To unsubscribe, click the “unsubscribe” link at the bottom of the email newsletter.
  * Block cookies.  Certain browsers may be configured to notify you when you receive cookies or allow you to restrict or disable certain cookies.  If you choose to disable cookies, however, that could affect certain features that use cookies to enhance their functionality.
  * Opt out of internet-based advertising.  For more information about third-party ad networks and services that use these technologies, you can visit [www.aboutads.info](http://www.aboutads.info/) and click [here to opt out](http://optout.aboutads.info/?c=2#!/) or to learn more about your options.  You also may visit the NAI’s site for additional options on how to opt out of interest-based advertising.

### **EEA RESIDENTS:**

If you are located in the EEA, or if otherwise required by applicable law, you have these additional rights and choices in relation to your personal information:

  * **Inspection and Access:**   You can request from us a summary and a copy of any personal information we hold about you.
  * **Correction/Addition/Removal:**   If you believe your information is inaccurate or incomplete, you are entitled to request us to correct, amend or delete it.
  * **Portability:**   You may request that we send you any personal information that you have provided to us or ask that we send this information to a third party.
  * **Objection:   **You may object to us using your personal information where we use it based on our legitimate interests to do so.
  * **Restriction:   **You may request that we restrict the processing of your information where you believe it is inaccurate, our processing is unlawful, you believe we no longer need the information or if you have objected to our use of it.
  * **Automated Decision Making:   **Where we undertake automated decision making (including profiling) which significantly affects you, you are entitled to object to such decision-making.
  * **Lodge a Complaint:   **You always have the right to lodge a complaint with the relevant supervisory authority for data protection in your jurisdiction.

### CALIFORNIA RESIDENTS

Subject to certain limits, under California law, California residents may ask us to provide them with a list of the categories of personal information that we have disclosed to third parties for those third parties’ direct marketing purposes during the preceding calendar year, as well as the identity of those third parties. California residents may contact us as specified in the “Contact Us” section below to make a request for this information.  See more at <http://consumercal.org/california-online-privacy-protection-act-caloppa/#sthash.0FdRbT51.dpuf>

### CHILDREN’S PRIVACY

Protecting the privacy of young children is especially important.  For that reason, we do not knowingly collect or solicit personal information from anyone under the age of 13.  If you are under 13, please do not send any information about yourself to us, including your name, address, telephone number, or email address.  No one under age 13 is allowed to provide any information on this website. In the event that we learn that we have collected personal information from a child under age 13 without verification of parental consent, we will delete that information as quickly as possible.  If you believe that we might have any information from or about a child under 13, please contact us at **carol@fromachefskitchen.com.**

### LINKS TO OTHER WEBSITES

This website includes links for your use and reference.  We make every effort to only link to safe, valid websites as this additional service to you.  We may occasionally include or offer third party products or services on our website.  You should be aware that the privacy policies of these sites may differ from From A Chef’s Kitchen.  Nonetheless, we seek to protect the integrity of our site and welcome any feedback about these sites.  However, we are not responsible for the practices employed by websites we may link to, nor the information or content contained therein.  Please remember that when you use a link to go from this website to another website, our Privacy Policy is no longer in effect.  Your browsing and interaction on any other website, including those that have a link on our website, is subject to that website’s own rules and policies.  Please read over those rules and policies before proceeding.

### CAN-SPAM ACT

The CAN-SPAM Act is a law in the United States that sets the rules for commercial e-mail practices, establishes requirements for commercial messages, gives recipients the right to have emails stopped from being sent to them, and spells out tough penalties for violations.

We collect your email address in order to send information, respond to inquiries, and/or other requests or questions.  To be in accordance with CAN-SPAM we agree to the following:

**      •** To NOT use false, or misleading subjects or email addresses

**      •** Identify the message as an advertisement in some reasonable way

**      •** Include the physical address of our business or site headquarters

**      •** Monitor third party email marketing services for compliance, if one is used.

**      •** Honor opt-out/unsubscribe requests quickly

**      •** Allow users to unsubscribe by using the link at the bottom of each email.  We will promptly remove you from ALL correspondence.
